Guide to Donald Phillips Papers RG.053
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Donald Phillips Papers
1966-1988
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Phillips, Donald S. (Donald Phillips), 1949-
RG.053
5 Linear Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These materials were gifted to the Poly Archives by Donald Phillips in June 2022.
Arrangement
This collection is housed in six boxes and arranged into five series: Series I Behavioral Effects of ELF/New York State Powerlines Project, 1982-1988 Series II 6-Hydroxydopamine Model for Schizophrenia, 1977-1984 Series III Acid Rain, 1982 Series IV Effect of Toxic Substances on Goldfish Behavior, 1970-1987 Series V Other Projects, 1966-1981. Original order was maintained whenever possible. There was some reorganization of folders for series placement under specific projects.
Biographical / Historical
Donald Smith Phillips was born on January 2, 1949 in New York City. He is a psychologist and senior lecturer within the Technology, Culture and Society department at NYU Tandon School of Engineering (Polytechnic Institute of New York University). He received his Bachelor of Science in Psychology from Polytechnic Institute of New York in 1979 and his Master of Science in Psychology from Polytechnic Institute of New York in 1991.
Phillips received a research grant to work on the New York State Power Lines project from 1982-1986, and most of the Donald Phillips Papers document this project. He has received the Teacher of Excellence award and Conger-Paterson award from Hofstra University in 1987 and 1989, respectively, and the Teacher of the Year award from the Nassau Association for Continuing Education in 1989. Additionally, he is a member of the New York Academy of Sciences and the New York Paleontological Society, where he has been president since 1982.
Scope and Contents
The Donald Phillips Papers contain documents from 1966 to 1988. These documents were assembled by Phillips throughout his professional career at Brooklyn Poly (operating under the names of Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (1900-1973), Polytechnic Institute of New York (1973-1985), Polytechnic University (1985-2008), and Polytechnic Institute of New York University). The collection contains laboratory project documentation and equipment. Documents include laboratory raw data and graphs, reports and project proposals, notes and reprints of research articles.The collection is five linear feet, located on bay 26, shelves 2B-4B.
Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; Psychology; Reprints; Laboratory notes
- Series I: Behavioral Effects of ELF/New York State Powerlines Project, 1982-1988
  - Sub-series A: Correspondence, 1983
    - ELF - Communications, 1983-10-04 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ELF Notes and Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series B: Equipment, undated
    - L.S. 103 Number 16 Embryology Microscope Slides, undated (Box 3, Item 1)
    - L.S. 103 Dr. Simmons Embryology Microscope Slides, undated (Box 3, Item 2)
    - Leeds & Northrup Kelvin Bridge Ohmmeter No. 4285, undated (Box 5, Item 1)
    - Gerbrands Model C-3 Cumulative Recorder, undated (Box 6, Item 1)
    - Lehigh Valley Electronics, undated (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Sub-series C: General Information, undated
    - ELF Running Schedules, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Field Exposure Apparatus, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - ELF - Photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series D: Proposals and Abstracts, 1982-1986
    - ELF NIH Proposal 2186, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - ELF Proposal 1/82, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - ELF Proposal, 1982-03-26-1982-03-30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Dept. of Health and Human Services Grant Application, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - ELF - BEM Abstract for June 1985 San Francisco (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - ELF EPA Proposal, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - NIH Resubmit Proposal 9/86, 1986-09 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - N.I.H ELF Proposal - Worksheets, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Effect of Electromagnetic Fields on the Behavior of Rats Project Proposal, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sub-series E: Raw Data and Graphs, 1982-1988
    - Temp. - Humidity Records Hillman Bldg.-ELF, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Graph Labels, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - ELF - Graphs and Tables from Dec. 1983 Progress Report, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Recognition Data 10/82, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - ELF Pilot Matching to Sample Mult-Match, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Item Response Theory (IRT) Group 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Statistics on ELF/SHAM Rat Weights, 1985-05-20 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Magnetic Field Amplitude Measurement, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Response to Carpenter, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Final Report (Update), 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - ELF - Publication Graphs, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Dr. Carpenter - Graphs in Body of Report, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - ELF Data Set I, I Moms, II, III Moms, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - R.I. Data, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - R.I. Data 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - R.I. Graphs, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Sub-series F: Reference, 1982
    - Ultrasound Exposure Article, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Electromagnetic Field Research and Notes, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - ELF Research File 5/82, 1982-05 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior Volume 19, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Behavior, Stimuli and Memory Articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Response Subclasses, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Stimulus Control, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Electroconvulsive Shock (ECS) Reprinted Articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Sub-series G: Reports, 1982-1987
    - Site Visit Report 8/30/84, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - ELF Progress Reports, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Behavioral Effects of ELF: Contractor's Final Report, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Behavioral Effects of ELF: Progress Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - ELF Progress Report July 1982 - Dec 1982 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Series II: 6-Hydroxydopamine Model for Schizophrenia, 1977-1984
  - 6-OHDA Rat Research, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - 6-OHDA Experiment Grant Application, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - 6-OHDA Research Plan, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Inhalants Research, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Drugs - Behavior, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Series III: Acid Rain, 1982
  - Acid Rain Proposal 8/82, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Series IV: Effect of Toxic Substances on Goldfish Behavior, 1970-1987
  - N.I.H. Proposal Goldfish 6/1/87, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Progress Report on the Goldfish - Pollution Project, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Goldfish-Pollution Research, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Goldfish-Pollution Data, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Worm Dispenser Drawings, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series V: Other Projects, 1966-1981
  - Sub-series A: Caffeine Rats, 1978-1981
    - Caffeine Data, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Caffeine Rats - Rat #80 Multiple Sch. 8/79 (1), 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Caffeine Rats - Rat #80 Multiple Sch. 8/79 (2), 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Sub-series B: Sleep Behavior, 1966-1981
    - Sleeping Behavior in Relation to Post VI Performance Log, 1976-04-26 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - CR Magnitude Pre-CS Levels (Based on Bin Medians), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Sleep Learning, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Sleep References, 1966-1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)